The prophet sallallahu alayhi
wa ala salam
told us about qiyamun laid.
In a lot of ahadith,
how about the one who does
not
sleep?
He prays throughout the
night.
This is ghalou fideen.
It's ghalou fideen, not to
sleep at
all, it's ghalou.
The same way we are
encouraged to
fast during the daytime,
are we?
How about the one who every
day
is fasting?
Every day is fasting.
So look at him.
Every day he is fasting
during daytime.
Every day he is on qiyamun
laid.
He is not sleeping.
The prophet condemned it,
sallallahu alayhi wa ala
salam.
Another aspect of ghalou
fideen.
A man has a wife and he
never comes near her.
Or a woman who never allows
her
husband to come near her.
Why?
She is busy with ibadah.
I'm busy with ibadah.
And all of these,
these are aspects of ghalou
fideen.
You see that ghalou,
the basics of that thing will
be
there.
But you'll be doing it in a
manner that goes beyond
limits.
Like fasting.
Yes, we should fast.
Beyond limit.
No fasting should go beyond
fast a
day, live a day.
That's so mudawud.
Except you fast three days in
a
month.
Maybe one at the beginning,
one at the middle,
one at the end.
Or you fast three straight
days.